Horace Gregory Papers
Horace Gregory Papers
1920-1973
Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982
12.25 linear ft.
Papers of the American poet, literary critic, scholar. Correspondence which is of greatest depth and duration includes letters from William Rose Benet, Winifred Bryher, Eleanor Clark, Malcolm Cowley, E.E. Cummings, Hilda Doolittle, Richard Eberhart, James Farrell, Dudley Fitts, John Gould Fletcher, Joseph Freeman, Robert Hillyer, Raymond E. F. Larsson, Norman Holmes Pearson,James Putnam, Muriel Rukeyser, Evelyn Scott, Winfield Townley Scott, John Sweeney, Allen Tate, M.B. Thornton, Louis Untermeyer, T.C. Wilson, and Morton Zabel.
146293
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Horace Gregory Papers comprise 26 archival boxes of material and include a Correspondence-Subject File, Writings and Memorabilia. A considerable proportion of this collection refers to Gregory's wife, Pulitzer Prize-winning poet, Marya Zaturenska, with much of the correspondence addressed to both parties, and some of the writings being collaborative efforts.
The Correspondence-Subject File is arranged alphabetically in 15 archival boxes, and includes biographical and family material as well as business and personal letters. The correspondence which is of greatest depth and duration includes letters from William Rose Benet, Winifred Bryher, Eleanor Clark, Malcolm Cowley, E. E. Cummings, Hilda Doolittle, Richard Eberhart, James Farrell, Dudley Fitts, John Gould Fletcher, Joseph Freeman, Robert Hillyer, Raymond E. F. Larsson, Norman Holmes Pearson, James Putnam, Muriel Rukeyser, Evelyn Scott, Winfield Townley Scott, John Sweeney, Allen Tate, M. B. Thornton, Louis Untermeyer, T. C. Wilson, and Morton Zabel. With the exception of an odd carbon copy or two and an occasional letter which was written but never sent, there is almost no outgoing correspondence. The last box (15) of correspondence contains unsolicited mail which has been divided by content into literary, political, or miscellaneous, and is arranged alphabetically within those categories.
Writings has been divided according to type (i.e. books, essays, poetry, etc.), and person who produced them, such that within each category are the works by Gregory, followed by those of Marya Zaturenska, and finally those which were collaborative projects. Writings includes book manuscripts, with several drafts of Gregory's Dorothy Richardson: An Adventure in Self-Discovery and his autobiographical work, The House on Jefferson Street. Among Miss Zaturenska's Writings are a series of journals which were produced between 1932 and 1960.
The Memorabilia includes photographs and clippings.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Literature -- American Poetry; Literature -- American Fiction; Benét, William Rose, 1886-1950.; Bryher, 1894-1983.; Clark, Eleanor, 1913-1996.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Cummings, E. E. (Edward Estlin), 1894-1962.; Eberhart, Richard, 1904-2005; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Fitts, Dudley, 1903-1968.; Fletcher, John Gould, 1886-1950.; Freeman, Joseph, 1897-1965.; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; H. D. (Hilda Doolittle), 1886-1961.; Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961.; Larsson, Raymond Ellsworth, 1901-1991.; Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1909-1975.; Putnam, James.; Rukeyser, Muriel, 1913-1980.; Scott, Evelyn, 1893-1963.; Scott, Winfield Townley, 1910-1968.; Sweeney, James Johnson, 1900-1986.; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979.; Thornton, M. B.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Wilson, T. C.; Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1901-1964.; Zaturenska, Marya, 1902-1982.; New letters in America.; New masses.; American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- Women authors.; American poetry -- 20th century.; Literature -- History and criticism.; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century.; Poets, American -- 20th century.; Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Family correspondence
  - Horace/Marya (wife) (Box 1)
  - Horace/Marya/Joanna (daughter) (Box 1)
  - Horace/Marya/Patrick (son) (Box 1)
  - Marya/others, 1948; Marya to John S. Mayfield (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Floy (step-sister?) (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Jim (brother) (Box 1)
  - Gregory, Nancy (niece) (Box 1)
  - LeMieux Family (Jo Gregory LeMieux is sister) (Box 1)
  - Stevens, Maud (Patrick's nanny while parents travelled) (Box 1)
  - Ziegler, Gregory (grandson) (Box 1)
  - Ziegler, Sam and Fran (Joanna's in-laws) (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files
  - A, one folder (Box 2)
  - Abbe, George Bancroft, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Abramowitz, Isidore, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Academy of American Poets, 1961-1969 (Box 2)
  - Ackland, Valentine, See New Masses
  - Adams, J. Donald, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Adams, Leonie, 1949; undated (Box 2)
  - Adler, Edward, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Agee, James, undated (Box 2)
  - Agresti, Olivia Rossetti, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Alberts, Sydney Seymour, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Aldington, Hilda, See Doolittle, Hilda
  - Alexander, I. J., 1937 (Box 2)
  - Allen, Charles Albert, 1939 (Box 2)
  - Allen, Walter Ernest, 1937; 1967 (Box 2)
  - American Association of University Women, 1951-1956 (Box 2)
  - Ames, Elizabeth, 1938-1939; undated (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Eleanor (Mrs. Sherwood), 1957-1964; undated (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Lee, 1945; 1951 (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Warren D., 1967 (Box 2)
  - Angeli, Helen Rossetti, 1951; 1954 (Box 2)
  - Angleton, James J., 1939-1941; undated (Box 2)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1933; 1937 (Box 2)
  - Asch, Nathan, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Ashman, Richard, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Atkinson, Brooks, undated (Box 2)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Avrett, Robert, 1945 (Box 2)
  - B, one folder (Box 2)
  - Baker, Christina Hopkinson, 1949? (Box 2)
  - Baro, Gene, 1951-1952 (Box 2)
  - Barth, Edna, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Bauer, Marion, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Beilke, Marlan, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Belaief, Gail, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Belitt, Ben, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Benet, William Rose, 1938-1948; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bishop, Elizabeth, 1936-1949; undated (Box 2)
  - Bishop, John Peale, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Bitker, Marjorie M., 1971; 1973 (Box 2)
  - Black, John, 1935; 1940 (Box 2)
  - Blackmur, Richard P., 1936-1941 (Box 2)
  - Bliss, Eliot, 1936-1938 (Box 2)
  - Bliven, Bruce, 1933-1939 (Box 2)
  - Bloch, Marie Halun, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Bodenheim, Maxwell, 1930; undated (Box 2)
  - Bogan, Louise, 1937; 1943 (Box 2)
  - Boggs, Tom, 1941; undated (Box 2)
  - Boie, Mildred Louise, 1938; 1941,; 1946 (Box 2)
  - The Boston Globe, 1964; undated (Box 2)
  - Botteghe Oscure, 1953; undated (Box 2)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Brandeis, Irma, undated (Box 2)
  - Brandeis University Creative Arts Awards, 1962; 1967 (Box 2)
  - Bree, Germaine, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Brewer, Wilmon, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Bridgman, Richard, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Brinnin, John Malcolm, 1939; undated (Box 2)
  - Brooke, Tucker, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Frederick, 1964 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Rollo Walter, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Bruncken, Herbert, 1938 (Box 2)
  - Bryher, Winifred, 1934-1957; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Bryher, Winifred, 1958-1972; undated; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Burke, Kenneth, 1933-1937 (Box 3)
  - Burn, June, undated (Box 3)
  - Burnett, Hallie, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Burnett, Whit, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley, 1960-1971; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1948; 1957-1960 (Box 3)
  - Byrne, Eugene Hugh, 1951 (Box 3)
  - C, one folder (Box 3)
  - Caetani, Marguerite, See Botteghe Oscure
  - Calisher, Hortense, 1966; undated (Box 3)
  - Calmer, Alan, 1933 (Box 3)
  - Campbell, Joseph, 1946; 1957 (Box 3)
  - Camus, Albert, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Cane, Melville, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Cantwell, Robert, undated (Box 3)
  - Carmer, Carl, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Carpenter, Margaret Haley, 1960; 1966 (Box 3)
  - Casals, Pablo, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Chafee, Zechariah, 1956 (Box 3)
  - Chase, Sarah Hannum, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Cherrington, Edith Dewitt, 1937 (Box 3)
  - Chicago Review, 1957; undated (Box 3)
  - Childs, Marquis William, 1925 (Box 3)
  - Christian, Henry A., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Ciardi, John, 1956-1957 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Donald Lemen, 1943-1946 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Eleanor, 1935-1945; undated (Box 3)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Coblentz, Stanton A., 1945 (Box 3)
  - Cohen, William Howard, undated (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Arthur Prudden, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Carroll, 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Collier Books, 1962-1968 (Box 3)
  - Colum, Padraic and Mary, 1953 (Box 3)
  - Columbia University, 1933-1968 (Box 3)
  - Columbia University Press, 1944 (Box 3)
  - The Commonweal, 1956-1963 (Box 3)
  - Congdon, Alden Kirby, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Conroy, Jack, 1933-1935; undated (Box 3)
  - Cordell, William Howard, 1934 (Box 3)
  - Covici, Pascal, 1936-1963; undated (Box 3)
  - Covici, Friede Inc., 1933-1943 (Box 3)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1931-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Creekmore, Hubert, 1949; 1956 (Box 4)
  - Cummings, E. E., 1955-1961; undated (Box 4)
  - Cummings, Marion Morehouse, See Morehouse, Marion
  - Cuthbert, Clifton, 1933 (Box 4)
  - D, one folder (Box 4)
  - Dahlberg, Edward, 1930-1934 (Box 4)
  - Daly, James, 1937; undated (Box 4)
  - Damon, S. Foster, 1933-1965 (Box 4)
  - Day, Esther Worden, 1940-1942; undated (Box 4)
  - Day Lewis, Cecil, 1964; undated (Box 4)
  - DeFord, Miriam Allen, 1937 (Box 4)
  - DeLuca, Angelo, 1960-1964; printed material (Box 4)
  - Del Vecchio, Thomas, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Derleth, August, 1969; 1971 (Box 4)
  - Deutsch, Babette, 1933-1954; undated (Box 4)
  - Diamond, David, 1972; undated (Box 4)
  - Dodd, Mead & Company, 1955; 1957 (Box 4)
  - Donaldson, Scott, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Doolittle, Hilda, 1934-1961; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Doolittle, Hilda - "Christmas 1944" (Box 4)
  - Doolittle, Hilda - Helen in Egypt, Introduction by H. Gregory - page proofs (Box 4)
  - Doolittle, Hilda - Helen in Egypt, galleys; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Doubleday & Company, Inc., 1954-1968 (Box 4)
  - Doxtator, Richard W., 1968 (Box 4)
  - Draper, Theodore, 1937 (Box 4)
  - Drew, Elizabeth, 1941 (Box 4)
  - Drew, Fraser Bragg, 1950 (Box 4)
  - Dupee, Frederick Wilcox, 1937; undated (Box 4)
  - DuPlessis, Rachel Blau, 1968 (Box 4)
  - E, one folder (Box 4)
  - Eastman, Max, 1938; 1959,; undated (Box 4)
  - Eaton, Charles Edward, 1946 (Box 4)
  - Eaton, Evelyn, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Eberhart, Richard, 1937-1944; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Eberhart, Richard, poetry (Box 4)
  - Edward MacDowell Association, Inc., See MacDowell Colony
  - Eells, John Shepard, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns, 1931-1964 (Box 4)
  - Enck, John Jacob, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Encyclopaedia Judaica, 1964--1965 (Box 4)
  - The Encyclopedia Americana, 1963-1968 (Box 4)
  - Evans, Oliver Wendell, 1938 (Box 4)
  - F, one folder (Box 4)
  - Faber and Faber Ltd., 1955-1956 (Box 4)
  - Farrell, James T., 1931-1959; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Farrell, James T., 1960-1969; miscellany; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Farrell, James T., poetry (Box 5)
  - Farrell, James T., printed material; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Faulkner, William, 1956 (Box 5)
  - Fearing, Kenneth, undated (Box 5)
  - Finch, Roy, 1959 (Box 5)
  - Fitts, Dudley, 1937-1968; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Fitts, Dudley, poetry (Box 5)
  - Fitzgerald, Robert, 1936-1950; undated (Box 5)
  - Fitzhugh, Robert Tyson, 1970 (Box 5)
  - Fitzsimmons, James, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Flack, Marjorie, undated (Box 5)
  - Flammonde, Paris, 1959; undated (Box 5)
  - Flanner, Hildegarde, 1935-1945 (Box 5)
  - Fleming, Guy, 1960 (Box 5)
  - Fles, Barthold, 1937 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher, John Gould, 1941-1947; undated; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Flexner, James Thomas, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Foner, Mathew, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Frankenberg, Lloyd, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Freedgood, Morton, undated (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Joseph, 1933-1961 (Box 5)
  - Freeman, Mary, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Freygood, Steven, 1967 (Box 5)
  - Friar, Kimon, 1944 (Box 5)
  - Friedman, Philip Allan, 1953 (Box 5)
  - Fukuda, Rikutaro, 1962 (Box 5)
  - Funaroff, Sol, 1935 (Box 5)
  - Furness, Clifton Joseph, 1937; 1940 (Box 5)
  - G, one folder (Box 5)
  - Galler, David, 1964 (Box 5)
  - Gardner, Virginia, 1972 (Box 5)
  - Garrigue, Jean, 1963; 1965,; undated (Box 5)
  - Geddes, Virgil, 1954 (Box 5)
  - Gehman, Richard, 1948 (Box 6)
  - George, Adda, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Glaze, Andrew, 1953 (Box 6)
  - Glikin, Gloria, 1965-1967 (Box 6)
  - Godin, Alexander, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Goodman, Joseph (musician), 1943-1959 (Box 6)
  - Goodreau, William, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Goodson, Wilbur Chapman, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Gordon, Ambrose, 1959 (Box 6)
  - Greenberg, Eliezer, 1937; undated (Box 6)
  - Greenhood, David, 1935 (Box 6)
  - Greenleaf, Richard, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Greenslet, Ferris, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Grigson, Geoffrey, See New Verse
  - Grindea, Miron, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Gropper, William, presentation copy of "Ye Creepy Tape" sewed in binding of Joyce Kilmer's Trees and Other Poems - original story with illustrations (Box 6)
  - Grove Press, 1952-1970; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Gruening, Martha, 1933; undated (Box 6)
  - John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1951; 1957,; 1961 (Box 6)
  - H, one folder (Box 6)
  - H. D., See Doolittle, Hilda
  - Hadas, Moses, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Halich, Wasyl, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Halper, Albert, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Hamilton, Bobb, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Hampson, John, 1934-1939; undated (Box 6)
  - Hansen, Harry, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Hanson, Lida Siboni, 1935 (Box 6)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and Company, Inc., 1946-1960 (Box 6)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and World, Inc., 1964-1968 (Box 6)
  - Harnack, Curtis, 1960-1971; undated (Box 6)
  - Harper, Allanah, undated (Box 6)
  - Harris, Mark, 1950-1954 (Box 6)
  - Harris, Murray George, undated (Box 6)
  - Harrison, Charles Yale, 1933 (Box 6)
  - Harter, Evelyn, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Harvard University/Harvard College Library, 1936-1950 (Box 6)
  - Hayes, Alfred, undated (Box 6)
  - Heiby, Walter, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Henderson, Barbara, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Henrich, Edith Dodd, 1944; undated (Box 6)
  - Herald, Leon Srabian, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Herbst, Josephine, 1937; 1939,; undated (Box 6)
  - Herring, Robert, 1937 (Box 6)
  - Hicks, Granville, 1931-1937; undated (Box 6)
  - Hillyer, Robert Silliman, 1934-1953; undated; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Hoffman, Frederick John, 1951-1958 (Box 7)
  - Holberg, Ruth Langland, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Holmes, John, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Holmyard, Barbara Stranahan, 1962 (Box 7)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc., 1964-1970; undated (Box 7)
  - Homberger, Eric, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Honeyman, Tom John, 1964 (Box 7)
  - Hook, Sidney, 1934 (Box 7)
  - Horton, Philip, 1936 (Box 7)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company, 1951-1954 (Box 7)
  - Hoult, Norah, 1934-1938; undated (Box 7)
  - Howe, Irving, 1949-1950 (Box 7)
  - Howes, Barbara, 1956; 1958 (Box 7)
  - Hudson, Flexmore, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Humphries, Rolfe, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Hunt, Violet, undated (Box 7)
  - Hunter College of the City of New York, 1934-1935 (Box 7)
  - Huntington Hartford Foundation, 1955-1956 (Box 7)
  - I, one folder (Box 7)
  - Ignatow, David, 1960? (Box 7)
  - Indiana University Writers' Conference, 1944-1950 (Box 7)
  - International Institute of Arts and Letters, 1957 (Box 7)
  - J, one folder (Box 7)
  - Jacobsen, Josephine, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Jeffers, Robinson, 1958 (Box 7)
  - Robinson Jeffers Committee of Occidental College, 1962-1967 (Box 7)
  - Robinson Jeffers Newsletter, 1962-1973; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Jobes, Gertrude, 1954 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Ben, 1952; 1954 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Edgar, 1973 (Box 7)
  - Jones, Howard Mumford, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Josephson, Hannah, undated (Box 7)
  - Josephson, Matthew, 1935 (Box 7)
  - K, one folder (Box 7)
  - Kallen, Horace Meyer, 1942 (Box 7)
  - Kallet, Arthur, 1935 (Box 7)
  - Kazin, Alfred, 1949; 1955-1956,; undated (Box 7)
  - Kees, Weldon, 1937-1943 (Box 7)
  - Kennedy, Lucy, undated (Box 7)
  - Kent, Richard, 1960; 1965 (Box 7)
  - Kerpely, Theresa de, 1958-1961; undated (Box 7)
  - Kiachif, Marcia, See Silvette, Marcia
  - Klein, I. (and Anna), 1934-1937 (Box 7)
  - Knickerbocker, William Skinkle, 1945 (Box 7)
  - Kray, Elizabeth, 1959 (Box 7)
  - L, one folder (Box 7)
  - Ladd, Henry Andrews, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Ladies' Home Journal, 1949-1954 (Box 7)
  - Lane, Rose Wilder, 1933 (Box 7)
  - Larsson, Karl, undated (Box 7)
  - Larsson, Raymond E. F., 1933-1940; undated; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Lattimore, Richard, 1950-1951; 1964 (Box 7)
  - Laughlin, James -, 1937; 1939,; 1949,; 1967 (Box 7)
  - Lazare, Christopher, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Leader, Pauline, 1933; undated (Box 7)
  - Lechlitner, Ruth, 1935; undated (Box 7)
  - Lehmann, John, 1937 (Box 7)
  - Leiser, Clara, 1935; 1937 (Box 7)
  - Lennon, Florence Becker, 1946 (Box 7)
  - Leon, Stephanie, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Leonard, William Ellery (and Grace), 1923-1941; undated (Box 7)
  - Leonard, William Ellery - "A Man Against Time", ms. (Box 7)
  - Leslie, Alfred, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Levinger, Leah, 1937-1938; undated (Box 8)
  - Lewis, H. H., 1935 (Box 8)
  - Lewis, Wyndham, 1940 (Box 8)
  - Library of Congress, 1944; 1955,; 1968 (Box 8)
  - Lieber, Maxim, 1934 (Box 8)
  - Little, Brown and Company, 1961; 1968 (Box 8)
  - Livingstone, Myra Cohn, 1963 (Box 8)
  - Lockwood Memorial Library, 1937-1954 (Box 8)
  - Loeb, Janice, undated (Box 8)
  - Logan, John, 1953-1961 (Box 8)
  - Logan, John, poetry (Box 8)
  - Lowell, Robert, undated (Box 8)
  - Lowenthal, Marvin, 1933; 1935 (Box 8)
  - Lowenthal, Sylvia M., 1940; undated (Box 8)
  - Lutyens, Elisabeth, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Lynd, Helen, 1940; 1960,; undated (Box 8)
  - M, one folder (Box 8)
  - Maas, Willard, 1937 (Box 8)
  - McCullough, Esther Morgan, 1956 (Box 8)
  - MacDiarmid, Hugh, 1941-1942 (Box 8)
  - MacDonald, Jessica Nelson North, 1936 (Box 8)
  - MacDowell Colony, 1953-1960 (Box 8)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, Inc., 1954-1958 (Box 8)
  - MacInnes, Duncan A., 1937 (Box 8)
  - McIntosh, Mavis, See McIntosh, McKee, and Dodds Inc.
  - McIntosh, McKee, and Dodds Inc., 1954-1965 (Box 8)
  - MacKay, Louis Alexander, 1958 (Box 8)
  - McMaster, Helen Neill, 1940-1944 (Box 8)
  - Macmillan Company, 1934-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - MacPherson, Perdita, 1950 (Box 8)
  - Maddow, Ben, 1937 (Box 8)
  - Madison, Charles Allan, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Malanga, Gerard, 1963-1966 (Box 8)
  - Mann, Klaus, 1936; 1944 (Box 8)
  - Mansfield, Margery, 1933; 1954,; undated (Box 8)
  - Mann, John, exhibition invitation (Box 8)
  - Marshall, Lenore, 1936; 1937,; 1942 (Box 8)
  - Matthiessen, Francis Otto, undated (Box 8)
  - Merriam, Eve, 1942 (Box 8)
  - Metcalfe, John, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Meynell, Francis, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Michelson, Herman, 1934; 1937 (Box 8)
  - Miles, Josephine, 1936; undated (Box 8)
  - Miller, Fred R., 1937 (Box 8)
  - Millett, Fred Benjamin, 1937 (Box 8)
  - Mills, Clark, 1936; 1937,; undated (Box 8)
  - Millspaugh, Clarence Arthur, 1937 (Box 8)
  - The Milwaukee Journal, 1954; 1964-1965 (Box 8)
  - University of Minnesota, 1967 (Box 8)
  - Moffitt, John, 1959 (Box 8)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1928-1935 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Elisabeth Luce, 1936 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Harry T., 1959; 1964 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1935-1955 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Merrill, 1935; 1936 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Nicholas, 1944-1945 (Box 8)
  - Morehouse, Marion, 1957-1966; undated (Box 8)
  - Morehouse, Ward, 1938; 1955 (Box 8)
  - Morley, F. V., 1950 (Box 8)
  - Morrison, Lillian, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Morrison, Theodore, 1944 (Box 9)
  - Morse, Carl, undated (Box 9)
  - Mumford, Lewis, 1928-1970; undated (Box 9)
  - Munson, Gorham, 1937; 1958-1960 (Box 9)
  - N, one folder (Box 9)
  - Nachman, Gerald, undated (Box 9)
  - The Nation, 1956-1962 (Box 9)
  - National Book Awards, 1950-1957 (Box 9)
  - National Cyclopedia of American Biography, 1933; 1938,; 1951 (Box 9)
  - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1942-1972
    - Membership nominations and ballots, 1964-1973; 4 folders (Box 9)
  - National Poetry Foundation, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Naul, Eric, See Young, Kathleen Tankersley
  - Nelson, Starr, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Thomas Nelson & Sons, 1959-1961 (Box 9)
  - Nemerov, Howard, 1942; undated (Box 9)
  - Nerber, John, 1948 (Box 9)
  - Neville, Helen, 1937 (Box 9)
  - New American Library, 1953-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - New Directions, 1959; 1964,; 1967 (Box 9)
  - New Masses, 1933-1939; undated (Box 9)
  - The New Quarterly, undated (Box 9)
  - The New Republic, 1934-1960 (Box 9)
  - New School for Social Research, 1941; 1953,; 1954 (Box 9)
  - New Theatre, 1935-1937 (Box 9)
  - New Verse, 1933-1937 (Box 9)
  - New York Herald Tribune, 1933-1938; 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - The New York Times, 1954-1970 (Box 9)
  - New York University Press, 1962 (Box 9)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1951 (Box 9)
  - Nims, John Frederick, 1947-1969 (Box 9)
  - Nock, Samuel Albert, 1938 (Box 9)
  - Norman, Charles, 1957-1968 (Box 9)
  - Norman, Dorothy, 1958; undated (Box 9)
  - North, Jessica Nelson, See MacDonald, Jessica Nelson North
  - North, Joseph, 1933-1939 (Box 9)
  - W. W. Norton and Company, Inc., 1937 (Box 9)
  - Nuhn, Ferner, 1931-1955 (Box 9)
  - O, one folder (Box 10)
  - O'Conor, Norreys Jephson, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Odle, Rose, 1960-1972; undated (Box 10)
  - O'Sheel, Shaemas, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Ostroff, Anthony, 1959-1960; undated (Box 10)
  - Oxford University Press, 1958-1968 (Box 10)
  - P, one folder (Box 10)
  - Palmer, Winthrop, undated (Box 10)
  - Pantheon Books, 1950-1956; 1963 (Box 10)
  - Partisan Review, 1953-1961 (Box 10)
  - Patchen, Kenneth, 1941; 1943 (Box 10)
  - Pauker, John (and Virginia), 1942-1945; 1967 (Box 10)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1937-1970; undated; miscellany; 8 folders (Box 10)
  - P. E. N., 1954-1969 (Box 10)
  - Perry, Stella George (Stern), 1935 (Box 10)
  - Pettinella, Dora M., 1963 (Box 10)
  - Peyre, Henri M., 1952-1957 (Box 10)
  - Phelps, Donald, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Phillips, Robert, 1971 (Box 10)
  - Pickering, John M., 1957; 1965 (Box 10)
  - Playter, Phyllis, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Plenn, Abel, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Poetry, 1944-1963; undated; See also Monroe, Harriet (Box 10)
  - Poetry Institute, Inc., See Morehouse, Ward
  - Poetry London - New York, 1955-1968 (Box 10)
  - Poetry Society of America, 1949-1968 (Box 10)
  - Pomeroy, William J., undated (Box 10)
  - Popkin, Henry, 1945 (Box 10)
  - Porter, Arabel J., See New American Library
  - Porter, Kenneth Wiggins, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Posner, David, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - Powell, Lawrence Clark, 1937 (Box 10)
  - Powys, Elizabeth Myers, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Prokosch, Frederic, 1938; 1943,; undated (Box 11)
  - Pulitzer Prize, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Puma, Fernando, 1953 (Box 11)
  - Purdy, James, 1956; 1958 (Box 11)
  - Putnam, James, 1936-1948; undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Q, one folder (Box 11)
  - Quinn, Kerker, 1937 (Box 11)
  - R, one folder (Box 11)
  - Rajan, Balachandra, 1945 (Box 11)
  - Rakosi, Carl, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Rannells, John, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Rao, Raja, 1971; undated (Box 11)
  - Reely, Mary Katharine, 1933; 1934,; undated (Box 11)
  - Replansky, Naomi, 1937; undated (Box 11)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, 1937-1949; undated (Box 11)
  - Richardson, Dorothy, 1934; 1939 (Box 11)
  - Ridge, Lola, undated (Box 11)
  - Riegel, Oscar Wetherhold, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Rinehart (Publishers), 1949-1958 (Box 11)
  - Roche, Paul, 1959 (Box 11)
  - Rodman, Selden, 1933-1964; undated (Box 11)
  - Roe, Ivan, 1938 (Box 11)
  - Roesch, Kurt, 1957 (Box 11)
  - Roethke, Theodore, 1937-1960; undated (Box 11)
  - Rolfe, Edwin, 1935-1937; undated (Box 11)
  - Rood, John, 1936 (Box 11)
  - Rorem, Ned, 1971 (Box 11)
  - Rosati, Salvatore, 1957; 1969 (Box 11)
  - Rosen, Aaron Tani, undated (Box 11)
  - Rosenberg, Harold, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Roskolenko, Harry, 1949 (Box 11)
  - Rosten, Norman, 1937 (Box 11)
  - Roth, Henry, 1933 (Box 11)
  - Mark Rothko Foundation, Inc., 1972 (Box 11)